pedigreedatabase.com 2011-12-31

# Privacy Statement - The Pedigree Database - German Shepherd Dog

> 1.      What personally identifiable information pedigreedatabase.com collects.
> 
> 2.      What personally identifiable information third parties collect through the Web site.
> 
> 3.      What organization collects the information.
> 
> 4.      How pedigreedatabase.com uses the information.
> 
> 5.      With whom pedigreedatabase.com may share user information.
> 
> 6.      What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information.
> 
> 7.      What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under pedigreedatabase.com control.
> 
> 8.      How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information.
> 
> If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact Olafur Tryggvason by [ oli@pedigreedatabase.com](mailto:oli@pedigreedatabase.com). 
> 
> ##  Information Collection and Use
> 
> ###  Information Collection
> 
> pedigreedatabase.com is the sole owner of the information collected on pedigreedatabase.com. pedigreedatabase.com collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site.
> 
> ###  Registration
> 
> In the areas of this Web site where a user must first complete a registration form.  During registration a user is required to give contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which he has expressed interest.  It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender), and unique identifiers (such as, username and password), but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site.   
> 
> ###  Information Use
> 
> pedigreedatabase.com does **not** disclose any of its information to third party members.  The information kept at pedigreedatabase.com is for the use of pedigreedatabase.com and none other.  This includes selling pedigree data,  pictures, user / contact information or any other privately kept data.  
> 
> ###  Cookies
> 
> A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user.  [Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site.]  We use [both] session ID cookies [and] persistent cookies.  For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates.  A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user's hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions.    
> 
> pedigreedatabase.com only uses cookies to track logged in users   By setting a cookie on our site, users would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site.  If users reject the cookie, they may still use our site.  The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site.  For example, the user will not be able to participate in any information submission which requires the user to be logged in. Persistent cookies enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site and keep the user from having to log in every time he visits pedigreedatabase.com. 
> 
>  Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers).  However, we have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. 
> 
> ###  Third Party Advertising
> 
> The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to users by online advertising brokers. Information about users' visit to this site, such as number of times they have viewed an ad (but not user name, address, or other personal information), is used to serve ads to users on this site.  
> 
> This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by pedigreedatabase.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 
> 
> ###  Log Files
> 
> Like most standard Web site servers we use log files.  This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.  IP addresses, etc. Are not linked to personally identifiable information.  We use a tracking utility called Funnel Web that uses log files to analyze user movement.
> 
> ###  Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)
> 
> We **do not** employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective.  Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. The main difference between the two is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence.
> 
> ##  Communications from the Site
> 
> ###  Special Offers and Updates
> 
> We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.
> 
> ###  Service Announcements
> 
> On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement.  For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email.  Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account.  However, these communications are not promotional in nature.  
> 
> ###  Customer Service
> 
> We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the users wishes.
> 
> ##  Sharing
> 
> ###  Legal Disclaimer
> 
> Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.
> 
> ###  Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)
> 
> We share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers.   This is not linked to any personally identifiable information.
> 
> ###  Third Party Advertisers
> 
> pedigreedatabase.com shares Web site usage information about users with a reputable third party for the purpose of targeting our Internet banner advertisements on this site and other sites.  The information they collect and share through this technology is not personally identifiable. 
> 
>   * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site.
>   * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet.
>   * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).
> 

> 
> We **DO NOT** Share Personal Information with Third Parties]
> 
> ###  Choice/Opt-out
> 
> Our users are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for information.  For example, our order form has an 'opt-out' mechanism so users who buy a product from us, but don't want any marketing material, can keep their email address off of our lists.  This only applies to users which have registered. We do not keep any personally identifiable information on non-registered visitors.
> 
> ###  Links
> 
> This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, pedigreedatabase.com, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.  We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.  This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.  
> 
> ###  Surveys
> 
> From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys.  Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information.  The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code).   Anonymous Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.  Users' personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties unless we give prior notice and choice. Though we may use an intermediary to conduct these surveys or contests, they may not use users' personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.
> 
> ###  Tell-A-Friend
> 
> If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend's name and email address.  pedigreedatabase.com will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site.  pedigreedatabase.com stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.  The friend may contact pedigreedatabase.com at support@pedigreedatabase.com to request the removal of this information from our database.
> 
> ###  Chat Rooms, Message Boards, and Public Forums
> 
> Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, by posting personal information online that is publicly accessible, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.
> 
> ###  Security
> 
> This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users' information.  When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line.
> 
> If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to support@pedigreedatabase.com
> 
> ###  Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information
> 
> If a user¿s personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users¿ personally identifiable information. This can usually be done at the member information page or by emailing us at support@pedigreedatabase.com.
> 
> ###  Notification of Changes
> 
> If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.
